Kircheimer, Otto; Papers ger006
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Otto Kirchheimer Papers
1929-1972
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger006
4.67 cubic ft.
The Otto Kirchheimer Papers contain correspondence with colleagues, publishers and students, book reviews written by Kirchheimer, reviews and offprints published by his colleagues and associates, and research notes on the social and political context of law. Listings of his offprint collection, book reviews, and pamphlets, as well as a list of the books held in Otto Kirchheimer's personal library are in the autobiographical file.
Biographical Sketch
Otto Kirchheimer was born November 11, 1905 in Heilbronn, Germany, fourth son of Julius Kirchheimer and Friederike (Baer) Kirchheimer. He attended school in Heilbronn and Ettenheim, then attended the Universities of Muenster, Berlin, Koeln and Bonn, graduating magna cum laude from the latter in 1928. With his new law degree in hand he became a contributor to Die Gesellschaft and a lecturer in Political Science at German Trade Union Schools. He practiced law in Berlin from 1932 to 1933, leaving Germany in 1933 (he was briefly arrested) because of his Social Democratic Party work.
The next four years were spent in Paris writing and doing research for the International Institute of Social Research. It is here he started rewriting George Rusche's work Punishment and Social Structure for the Institute. This Rusche-Kirchheimer version of Punishment and Social Structure was published in 1939.
In 1937 Kirchheimer arrived in the United States while his wife Hilde, from whom he had been separated for years, and daughter Hanna remained in Europe. His marriage ended a few years later in divorce. While in New York, he continued to work for the International Institute of Social Research (Horchheimer Institute) as a research assistant in law and social science and lecturing in the Institute's program at Columbia University.
In 1943, Kirchheimer moved from New York to Washington, D.C. with his second wife Anne Rosenthal, who later bore his second child, Peter. He took a position as a part-time research analyst at the Research and Analysis Branch of the U. S. Office of Strategic Services. He remained employed with the OSS and later the State Department for thirteen years, eventually directing the total research activities of the Central European Branch. While at the State Department, Kirchheimer accepted part-time teaching positions at American University and Howard University. He left the State Department in 1955 to teach full time, accepting a professorship in the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research.
Kirchheimer stayed at the New School for five years, teaching and writing his second book Political Justice: The Use of Legal Procedures for Political Ends. In 1961, Kirchheimer accepted a position teaching at Columbia and continued to write for political science journals, contributed to books, and prepared position papers for international conferences. On November 22, 1965, while boarding a plane at Dulles airport on his way to teach at Columbia, Otto Kirchheimer suffered a fatal heart attack.
November 11, 1905 Born in Heilbronn to Julias and Frederike (Baer) Kirchheimer
1912-1924 Attended school in Heilbronn, Heidelberg, Ettenheim
1924-1928 Studied at the Universities of Muenster, Berlin, Koeln, Bonn
1928 Law degree (Dr. Jur.) magna cum laude, University of Bonn
19?? Married Hilde Rosenfeld
1930 Daughter, Hanna, born.
1930-1933 Contributed to Die Gesellschaft and lectured on Political Science at German Trade Union School
1932-1933 Practiced law in Berlin
1933-1937 Researcher in the Paris Branch of the International Institute of Social Research (Horkheimer Institute). Worked on Punishment and Social Structure.
November 11, 1937 Emigrated to the United States
1937-1942 Researcher in Law and Social Science for the Institute of Social Research. Lectured at Columbia University.
1941 Divorced Hilde Kirchheimer
1941 Married Anne Rosenthal
1943 Visiting lecturer in Sociology at Wellesley College
November 16, 1943 U. S. Citizenship granted
1943-1944 Part-time research analyst at the Research and Analysis Branch of the U. S. Office of Strategic Services (OSS)
1946 Son, Peter, born
1944-1952 Full-time research analyst at the OS
1952-1956 Chief, Central European Branch, OSS
1951-1952 Lecturer, Political Science, American University
1952-1954 Lecturer, Political Science, Howard University
1954-1955 Visiting Professor on the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research
1955-1961 Professor, Political Science, New School
1961 Completed work on Political Justice
1961-1962 Fulbright Professor, University of Freiburg
1960-1965 Professor, Political Science, Columbia University
November 22, 1965 Suffered fatal heart attack
Scope and Contents
The Otto Kirchheimer Papers (1929-1968) are of interest to researchers of constitutional law, criminal justice, and the political and social uses of law, as well as to those interested the the German exile experience. His correspondence shows a great interest in the emerging German nation and its new constitution, influential political parties and trade unions.
Kirchheimer's correspondence reveals a man very much respected by German politicians like Fritz Erler, one-time presidential candidate and Carlo Schmid, former vice-president of the German Bundestag. He remained in contact with Gerhard Schulz, labor leader, Ernst Friesenhahn, federal constitutional judge, and Adolf Arndt, long-time member of the Bundestag. Kirchheimer also corresponded with many other intellectuals world-wide. These include Arthur Bergman, Charles David, Horst Ehmke, Ernst Fraenkel, Arkadij Gurland, Arnold Heidenheimer, Wilhelm Hennis, Gerhard Kramer, Gerhard Loewenberg, Karl Loewenstein, Val Lorwin, Harvey Mansfield, Herbert Marcuse, Franz Neumann, Helge Pross, Helmut Ridder, Richard Schmid, and Rudolf Smend. His correspondence files include two letters from Hannah Arendt and one from Supreme Court Justice Felix Frankfurter.
The collection contains correspondence with colleagues, publishers and students (1927-1965). It includes numerous book reviews written by Kirchheimer (1937-1965), reviews and offprints published by his colleagues and associates (1913-1964), as well as extensive research notes on the social and political context of law. The collection also includes much of his personal library. Listings of his offprint collection, book reviews, and pamphlets, as well as a list of the books held in Otto Kirchheimer's personal library are in the autobiographical file.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Autobiographical Material, 1942-1968
Series 2: Professional Correspondence, 1927-1965
Series 3: Correspondence with Publishers, 1952-1965
Series 4: Writings, 1937-1964
Series 5: Kirchheimer's Testimony before the House Foreign Affairs Committee, June 29, 1964
Series 6: Reviews of Kirchheimer's Publications, 1939-1965
Series 7: Teaching and Research Notes, undated
Series 8: Research Materials, undated
Series 9: Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues, 1913-1964
Series 10: Political pamphlets, 1913-1969
Acquisition Information
All items were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Anne Kirchheimer on August 21, 1981.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Political Science; World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.; Constitutions -- Germany.; Political science.; Kirchheimer, Otto.; Bergman, Arthur.; Ehmke, Horst.; Erler, Fritz.; Friesenhahn, Ernst.; Schmid, Karl, 1896-
- Autobiographical Material, 1942-1968; 1; 3 file folders
  Scope and Contents
  Contains application for employment and personal history statement, list of publications, curriculum vitae, power of attorney and obituaries. Also includes a bibliography of Kirchheimer's personal library.
  - Vitae, Personal History Statement, List of Publications, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical Material), Folder 1)
  - Kirchheimer's Personal Library - List 1, 2, 3, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical Material), Folder 2)
  - Guggenheim/Social Science Research, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical Material), Folder 3)
- Professional Correspondence, 1927-1965; 2; 186 file folders
  Encompasses, but is not limited to, correspondence with professional colleagues about each other's research, narratives of projects, requests for critical analyses, as well as solicitations for articles, speeches and papers. Includes letters of recommendation, job offers, and petitions for research ideas from colleagues and students. Contains critical exchanges about the new German government, German elections, and the emerging political parties.
  Includes correspondence with Adolf Arndt, Hannah Arendt, Arthur Bergman, Charles David, Horst Ehmke, Fritz Erler, Ernst Fraenkel, Ernst Friesenhahn, Arkadi Gurland, Arnold Heidenheimer, Wilhelm Hennis, Gerhard Kramer, Gerhard Loewenberg, Val Lorwin, Karl Loewenstein, Harvey Mansfield, Herbert Marcuse, Franz Neumann, Helge Pross, Helmut Ridder, Richard Schmid, Carlo Schmid, Gerhard Schulz, and Rudolf Smend. Also contains modest correspondence with Max Horchheimer (1), Felix Frankfurter (1) and Hans Staudinger (3-4).
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - A -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - The Academy of Political Science, 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Achinger, H., 1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Adams, Leonard P., 1951; typescript (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Almond, Gabriel A., 1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1956-1959 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - American Political Science Association, 1961-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Arendt, Hannah, 1963; Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Arndt, Adolf, 1960-1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Ascher, Abraham, 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - B -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Backer, Samuel H., 1960 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Barnes, Samuel H., 1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Bauer, Fritz, 1957; 1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Bekker, Konrad, 1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Benjamin, Hilde, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Bergmann, Arthur, 1956-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Boenau, Arthur Bruce, 1961-1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Braunthal, Alfred, 1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Breithaupt, W., 1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Breugelmans, René, 1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Brodersen, Arvid, 1957-1958 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Brown, Benjamin H., 1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Butler, John Marshall, 1960 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Buxbaum, Richard, 1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - C, D -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Cate, Curtis, 1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Chapman, John W., 1962-1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Cohen, Steve, 1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Columbia University, 1960-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Committee on Foreign Affairs, Congress of the United States, 1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils, 1957-1958 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Daalder, Hans, 1961-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - Dahl, Robert A., 1962-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - David, Charles & Jeanne, 1961-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Department of State, 1957; 1960 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund, 1961-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Diamant, Alfred, 1959-1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - Drath, Martin, 1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - E, F -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Edinger, Lewis J., 1959 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Ehmke, Horst, 1956-1965; Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Ehrmann, Henry W., 1957-1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Emerson, Thomas, 1960-1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Epstein, Fritz T., 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 49)
  - Erler, Fritz, 1957-1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 50)
  - Eschenburg, Theodor, 1960-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 51)
  - Fabian, Doria, 1929-1930 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 52)
  - Fabian, Walter, 1961; 1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 53)
  - Faul, Erwin (Politische Vierteljahresschrift), 1961-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 54)
  - Finley, M. I., 1962-1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 55)
  - Flechtheim, Ossip & Lili, 1957-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 56)
  - Fraenkel, Ernst, 1964-1969 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 57)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1949 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 58)
  - Freund, Gerald, 1957-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 59)
  - Friedrich, Carl J., 1947; 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 60)
  - Friesenhahn, Ernst, 1948-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 61)
  - Fulbright Commission, 1960-1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 62)
  - G, H -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 63)
  - Gerth, Hans H., 1952-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 64)
  - Gray, Gordon, 1949 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 65)
  - Grosser, Alfred, 1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 66)
  - Gurian, Waldemar, ca. 1940s (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 67)
  - Gurland, Arkadij R. L., 1952-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 68)
  - Habermas, Juergen, 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 69)
  - Hardin, Charles, 1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 70)
  - Hartenstein, Wolfgang, 1962; 1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 71)
  - Heberle, Rudolf, 1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 72)
  - Heidenheimer, Arnold J., 1957-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 73)
  - Heimann, Eduard, 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 74)
  - Hennis, Wilhelm, 1956-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 75)
  - Hertz, Paul, 1957-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 76)
  - Herz, John H., Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 77)
  - Hesse, Konrad, 1957-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 78)
  - Hessischer Minister für Erziehung und Volksbildung, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 79)
  - Hessisches Staatsministerium, 1948 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 80)
  - Holborn, Hajo, 1956; 1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 81)
  - Horkheimer, Max, 1952 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 82)
  - Hughes, H. Stuart, 1956-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 83)
  - Hurtig, Serge, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 84)
  - I, J -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 85)
  - Johann Wolfgang Goethe-Universität, Frankfurt, 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 86)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1956; 1958 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 87)
  - K, L -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 88)
  - Kahn-Freund, Otto, 1956 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 89)
  - Kaufman, Irving R., 1959 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 90)
  - Kesten, Hermann, 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 91)
  - Kramer, Gerhard, 1947-1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 92)
  - Krippendorff, Ekkehart, 1961-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 93)
  - Kummermuss (Gewerkschaft öffentl. Dienste), 1952-1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 94)
  - Kutscher, Hans, 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 95)
  - LaPalombara, Joseph, 1961-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 96)
  - Laqueur, Walter, 1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 97)
  - Lavau, Georges, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 98)
  - Leibholz, Gerhard, 1953-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 99)
  - Leierson, Avery, 1960-1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 100)
  - Leites, Nathan, undated, 1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 101)
  - Linz, Juan, 1964; Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 102)
  - Loewenberg, Gerhard, 1960-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 103)
  - Loewenstein, Karl, 1955-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 104)
  - Loitlsberger, E., 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 105)
  - Lorwin, Val, 1954-1965; Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 106)
  - Lutz, Burkart, 1956-1957 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 107)
  - M, N -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 108)
  - MacPherson, C. B., 1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 109)
  - Marcuse, Herbert, 1959-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 110)
  - Massing, Paul, 1961 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 111)
  - Matthöfer, Hans & Traute, 1960-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 112)
  - Menges, Constantine, 1963-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 113)
  - Meyer, Fritz, 1937-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 114)
  - Moore, Barrington (Barry), Jr., 1961-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 115)
  - Morgenthau, Hans J., 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 116)
  - Morris, Bernard (Bernie) S., 1959-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 117)
  - Morrison, Phoebe, 1957-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 118)
  - Morse, Wayne, 1949 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 119)
  - Mosely, Philip, 1963-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 120)
  - Mueller, Gerhard O. W., 1956-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 121)
  - Neumann, Franz L., 1937-1948 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 122)
  - Neumann, Sigmund, 1960 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 123)
  - New School for Social Research, Graduate Faculty of Political and Social Science, 1958-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 124)
  - O, P -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 125)
  - Pachter, Henry M., 1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 126)
  - Pollock, Frederick, 1939; 1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 127)
  - Pollock, James K., 1960 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 128)
  - Pross, Helge, 1956-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 129)
  - R -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 130)
  - Ramm, Thilo, 1963-1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 131)
  - The Rand Corporation, 1956-1957 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 132)
  - Rheinstein, Max, 1963; 1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 133)
  - Ridder, Helmut, 1957-1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 134)
  - Riesenfeld, Alphonse, 1964 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 135)
  - Roche, John, 1963 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 136)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1948-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 137)
  - Rogers, Lindsay, 1949; 1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 138)
  - Rosenberg, J. Mitchell, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 139)
  - Rothstein, Siegmar, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 140)
  - S -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Safran, William, 1960-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Sanderson, Fred, 1959-1964 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Sartori, Giovanni, 1962-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Sauer, Wolfgang, 1962-1964 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Scannon, Richard M. (Office of the High Commissioner for Germany), 1950-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Scheuner, Ulrich, 1955-1962 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Schiedermaier, Dr. (Dekan der Rechtswissenschaftlichen Fakultät, Johann Wolfgang Goethe-Universität, Frankfurt), 1948-1949 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Schleck, Robert (Bob) W., 1959-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Schmid, Carlo, 1962 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Schmid, Richard, 1948-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Schmitt, Carl, 1958; Undated (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Schneider, Hans, 1960-1961 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Schorsch, Erich, 1961-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Schulz, Gerhard, 1960-1961 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Shell, Kurt L., 1962; 1964 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Silverman, Sondra J., 1961-1963 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Simons, Hans, 1955-1957 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Smend, Rudolf & Gisela, 1948-1952 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1962-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Sontheimer, Kurt, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Speier, Hans (The Rand Corporation), 1955-1961 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Spitz, David, 1956; 1962 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Stammer, Otto, 1951-1960 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Staudinger, Hans, 1956-1958 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Stern, Fritz, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Sternberg, Fritz, 1962 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Stiefbold, Rodney, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Stoddard, John C. (U.S. Information Service), 1961 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Stourzh, Gerald (John F. Kennedy-Institut für Amerikastudien), 1964 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Sturmthal, Adolf, 1957 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - T, U, V -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 32)